Guide to the University Archives Records, 1941-2004
Duke University. University Archives
University Archives records 1941-2004
Duke University. University Archives
Duke University Archives
25.5 linear feet Extent: 24,500 Items
Contains correspondence received by the Archives as well as patron registration forms, permission to publish forms, exhibit materials, supplies, labels and other information gathered/created by the Archives during day-to-day operations. The collection ranges in date from 1941-2004.
UA.08.08.0001
Language: Material in English
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
For a period of twenty-five years from the origin of the material, permission in writing from the office of origin and the University Archivist is required for use. After twenty-five years, records that have been processed may be consulted with the permission of the University Archivist.
Provenance
The University Archives Records were received by the University Archives as a transfer in 1972-2004, 2013.
Collection Overview
Contains correspondence received by the Archives as well as patron registration forms, permission to publish forms, exhibit materials, supplies, labels and other information gathered/created by the Archives during day-to-day operations. The collection ranges in date from 1941-2004.
Contents of Collection
- Container List, 52 Boxes
  - Patron Registration Forms, 1972-1982 (Box 1)
  - Patron Registration Forms, 1982-1988 (Box 2)
  - Patron Registration Forms, 1988-1991 (Box 3)
  - Patron Registration Forms, 1991-1994 June (Box 4)
  - Patron Registration Forms, 1994 July-1996 (Box 5)
  - Patron Registration Forms, 1997-2000 (Box 6)
  - Patron Registration Forms, 2001-2002 (Box 7)
  - Patron Registration Forms and Correspondence, 2003-2004 (Box 8)
  - Correspondence, 1972-1973 (Box 9)
  - Correspondence, 1974 (Box 10)
  - Correspondence, 1975 (Box 11)
  - Correspondence, 1976 (Box 12)
  - Correspondence, 1977 (Box 13)
  - 14, Correspondence, 1978 (Box 13)
  - Correspondence, 1979 (Box 15)
  - Correspondence, 1980 (Box 16)
  - Correspondence, 1981 (Box 17)
  - Correspondence, 1982 (Box 18)
  - Correspondence, 1983 (Box 19)
  - Correspondence, 1984 (Box 20)
  - Correspondence, 1985 (Box 21)
  - Correspondence, 1986 (Box 22)
  - Correspondence, 1987 (Box 23)
  - Correspondence, 1988 (Box 24)
  - Correspondence, 1989 (Box 25)
  - Correspondence, 1990 (Box 26)
  - Correspondence, 1991 (Box 27)
  - Correspondence, 1992 (Box 28)
  - Correspondence, 1993 (Box 29)
  - Correspondence, 1994 (Box 30)
  - Correspondence, 1995 (Box 31)
  - Correspondence, 1996 (Box 32)
  - Correspondence, 1997 (Box 33)
  - Correspondence, 1998 (Box 34)
  - Correspondence, 1999 (Box 35)
  - Subject Files, A-C, 1972-2001 (Box 36)
  - Subject Files, D-H, 1972-2001 (Box 37)
  - Subject Files, I-Pl, 1972-2001 (Box 38)
  - Subject Files, Pr-Z, 1972-2001 (Box 39)
  - Historical information regarding the formation of the Archives, 1941-1972 (Box 40)
  - Receipts of Records, 1972-1982 (Box 41)
  - Receipts of Records, 1982-1991 (Box 42)
  - Receipts of Records, 1991-2002 (Box 43)
  - Permission to publish or use restricted material records, 1981-2001 (Box 44)
  - Records of loans, includes records never returned, 1989- (Box 45)
  - Chapel Exhibit (Box 46)
  - Julian Abele Exhibit (Box 47)
  - Lilly Library Exhibit (Box 48)
  - President's Exhibit, 2004 "Uncommon Leaders, the President's of Duke University highlights from the Duke University Archives" (Box 49)
  - West Campus at 75 Exhibit (Box 50)
  - Exhibits - labels, ideas, reproductions (Box 51)
  - Exhibits file (Box 52)
    - Student Organization exhibit in main lobby, Spring 1996 (Box 52)
    - Duke Olympians, Summer/Fall 1996 (Box 52)
    - Women in Residence, 1896/1897-1996/1997 (Box 52)
    - Archives Exhibit, Fall 1997 (Box 52)
    - Broadcasting at Duke/WXDU Anniversary, Fall 1997 (Box 52)
    - Broadcasting at Duke: Fifty Years of Student Radio, Fall 1997 (Box 52)
    - Archives 25th Anniversary, September 1997 (Box 52)
    - The Woman's College, 1930-1972, Perkins Lobby November-December 2002 (Box 52)
    - Vigil/S.D. Cook Society Reception, February 1998 (Box 52)
    - The Silent Vigil: 30 Years Ago, Spring-Fall 1998 (Box 52)
    - Student Organization's Exhibit, 1998-1999 (Box 52)
    - Exhibit - Lilly Library April 1999 - The Alumni Association (Box 52)
    - Duke Originals, September-October 1999 - Perkins Lobby (75th Anniversary) (Box 52)
    - Meet Your Predecessors: Freshman Week…," September/October 1999 Lilly Library (Box 52)
    - The Alumni/Alumnae Associations, Lilly Library, May-August, 1999 (Box 52)
    - Student Life - Public and Private Spaces, Perkins Library, April 1999 (Box 52)
    - Duke Originals - September 1999 (Box 52)
    - What's for Dinner? Dining at Duke, September 1999-May 2000 (Box 52)
    - Roosevelt, Teddy - Visit to Trinity, 1905 (Box 52)
    - The Changing Faces of West Campus, 20 Years of Construction, 1982-2002 (Box 52)
    - The Knight Years, 1963-1969, Rare Book Room, October 2003 (Box 52)
    - Comment Book from the Woman's College exhibit (Box 52)
    - Hawley, Hughson - rendering of Duke Campus - West Campus exhibit (Box 52)
    - Construction photos: East Campus (Box 52)
    - Progress Photos (West Campus) (Box 52)
    - Union Institute Construction, 1838 (Box 52)
    - Trinity Catalogue, 1860-1861/ Trinity Magazine 1883 (Box 52)
    - Exhibits - 20/40 Celebration (Box 52)
    - Civil Rights Exhibit (Box 52)
    - Duke Presidents Exhibit (Box 52)
    - Undergraduate Publications Exhibit (Box 52)
  - Comments from "The Road to Desegregation at Duke" exhibit which ran from 2012 Dec.-2013 Mar. (Opaperfolder 1)